♪Fade like drifting clouds♪
♪تتلاشى مثل السحب المنجرفة♪
♪Half dream, half illusion♪
♪نصف حلم، ونصف وهم♪
♪Fated or fleeting♪
♪مقدر أو عابر♪
♪Spring breeze falls from my brow♪
♪نسائم الربيع تهب من جبهتي♪
♪Where to go, I do not know♪
♪أين أذهب، لا أعرف♪
♪I turn, and all is gone♪
♪أتحول، وكل شيء قد ذهب♪
♪Ask how deep the dust of love runs♪
♪اسأل عن مدى عمق غبار الحب♪
♪How strong longing grows♪
♪ما أشد الشوق الذي ينمو♪
♪I play till the final note♪
♪ألعب حتى النغمة الأخيرة♪
=In The Name of Loyalty=
=باسم الولاء=
=Episode 15=
=الحلقة 15=
My lord,
سيدي،
it's clear Shi Yu knew how damaging
من الواضح أن شي يو كان يعرف مدى الضرر
Her Grace's departure would be.
رحيل صاحبة السمو سيكون.
That's why he dared to humiliate you so.
ولهذا السبب تجرأ على إذلالك بهذه الطريقة.
I don't understand why you don't seize the throne yourself.
لا أفهم لماذا لا تستولي على العرش بنفسك.
You fool!
يا أحمق!
Are you asking me to kill the Emperor?
هل تطلب مني قتل الإمبراطور؟
Will you shoulder the infamy
هل ستتحمل العار؟
of regicide on my behalf?
من قتل الملك نيابة عني؟
I know I was wrong.
أعلم أنني كنت مخطئا.
- Where's Zhiying? - I know I was wrong.
- أين تشي ينغ؟ - أعلم أنني كنت مخطئا.
I know I was wrong.
أعلم أنني كنت مخطئا.
Have you not found Zhiying yet?
هل لم تجد Zhiying بعد؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
If you fail to locate my sister,
إذا فشلت في العثور على أختي،
you'll disappear permanently.
سوف تختفي للأبد.
Yes.
نعم.
Why did you suddenly...
لماذا فجأة...؟
Aren't you afraid of being seen?
ألا تخاف من أن يراك أحد؟
I want people to see this.
أريد الناس أن يروا هذا.
Before, I deliberately kept
في السابق، كنت أحتفظ بها عمدًا
my distance from trusted allies.
بعدي عن حلفائي الموثوق بهم.
- When secrets surfaced later, - Your Majesty.
- عندما ظهرت الأسرار في وقت لاحق، - جلالتك.
it gave Gao Ji justification to kill.
لقد أعطى هذا لجاوجي مبررًا للقتل.
To prevent Gao Ji from killing you,
لمنع غاو جي من قتلك،
I must show the world
يجب أن أظهر للعالم
that you belong to me.
أنك ملكي.
Shi Yu,
شي يو,
isn't this abusing your power for personal gain?
أليس هذا إساءة لاستخدام سلطتك لتحقيق مكاسب شخصية؟
How could this be considered abuse of power?
كيف يمكن اعتبار هذا إساءة لاستخدام السلطة؟
Come on.
تعال.
Return with me.
عد معي.
I have further plans.
لدي خطط أخرى.
They're gone.
لقد رحلوا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Is it ready?
هل هو جاهز؟
Do you like it?
هل أحببت ذلك؟
Since you're my waiting maid,
بما أنك خادمتي المنتظرة،
I'll gift you this splendid garment.
سأهدي لك هذه الملابس الرائعة.
Let me try it on.
دعني أجربه.
This time,
هذه المرة،
allow me to serve you.
اسمح لي أن أخدمك.
Who have you caught this time?
من الذي قمت بالقبض عليه هذه المرة؟
And why ask me to see?
ولماذا تطلب مني أن أرى؟
I saw her leaving the palace alone.
رأيتها تغادر القصر بمفردها.
I couldn't tell which consort she was.
لم أستطع أن أحدد أي زوجة كانت.
Help!
يساعد!
- But I thought - Let me go!
- ولكنني فكرت - دعني أذهب!
- she might aid your cause. - Who are you?
- قد تساعدك في قضيتك. - من أنت؟
Shut up.
اسكت.
- So - Let go of me!
- إذن - دعني أذهب!
- I took initiative - Let go!
- لقد اتخذت المبادرة - دعها تذهب!
- to bring her here. - Let go of me!
- لإحضارها إلى هنا. - دعني أذهب!
Hands off!
ابتعد عن يديك!
Let go of me!
أتركني!
Let go!
اتركه!
Gao Zhiying?
جاو زيينج؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
If you know who I am,
إذا كنت تعرف من أنا،
you must know my brother's identity.
يجب أن تعرف هوية أخي.
Gag her.
إسكتها.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
I'll have him exterminate your entire clan!
سأجعله يبيد عشيرتك بأكملها!
You said
أنت قلت
she left the palace alone?
تركت القصر وحده؟
Yes.
نعم.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Nobody witnessed the capture.
لم يشهد أحد عملية القبض عليه.
You know her?
هل تعرفها؟
This is the current Empress,
هذه هي الإمبراطورة الحالية
Gao Ji's younger sister.
أخت جاو جي الصغرى.
Had Gao Ji not betrayed you back then,
لو لم يخونك جاو جي في ذلك الوقت،
you wouldn't be reduced to this state.
لن تصل إلى هذه الحالة.
I'll kill her now.
سأقتلها الآن.
Wait.
انتظر.
Such a valuable piece
قطعة ثمينة جدا
would be wasted through execution.
سيتم إهدارها من خلال التنفيذ.
Now
الآن
Shi Yu
شي يو
and the Empress
والإمبراطورة
are both under my control.
كلاهما تحت سيطرتي.
Wouldn't the realm be mine?
ألا يكون هذا العالم ملكي؟
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
you'll personally guard her.
سوف تحرسها شخصيا.
No mistakes are tolerated.
لا يتم التسامح مع الأخطاء.
Yes, Master.
نعم سيدي.
Dismissed.
تم طرده.
Yes.
نعم.
Stay back!
ابقى في الخلف!
Don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
Cheng Ge, give it to me.
تشنغ جي، أعطني إياه.
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
Cheng Ge,
تشنغ جي,
just sit over there.
فقط اجلس هناك.
Cheng Ge, let me do it.
تشنغ جي، دعني أفعل ذلك.
Cheng Ge.
تشنغ قه.
Why weren't you my waiting maid today?
لماذا لم تكوني خادمتي اليوم؟
You should see.
ينبغي عليك أن ترى.
Now everyone competes to assist me.
الآن الجميع يتنافسون لمساعدتي.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
From now on, the waiting maid duty
من الآن فصاعدا، واجب الخادمة الانتظار
will solely fall upon you.
سوف تقع عليك وحدك.
You hear me?
هل تسمعني؟
What?
ماذا؟
I have to serve you?
هل يجب علي أن أخدمك؟
I'm suffering from poison now.
أنا أعاني من السم الآن.
Yesterday, I was helping you...
بالأمس كنت أساعدك...
They...
هم...
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
there is one more reason
هناك سبب آخر
why I didn't go today.
لماذا لم أذهب اليوم .
I thought about it. I need to report to Shi Nan.
فكرتُ في الأمر. عليّ إبلاغ شي نان.
Your previous words make sense.
كلماتك السابقة لها معنى.
If we can reverse our approach
إذا كان بوسعنا أن نعكس نهجنا
and use Shi Nan's influence,
واستخدام تأثير شي نان،
it would greatly aid in overthrowing Gao Ji.
من شأنه أن يساعد بشكل كبير في الإطاحة بجاو جي.
Since our goals align,
وبما أن أهدافنا تتوافق،
let's comply with Shi Nan's commands first.
دعونا نلتزم بأوامر شي نان أولاً.
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
You're surrounded by Gao Ji's spies.
أنت محاط بجواسيس جاو جي.
It's better if I go alone.
من الأفضل أن أذهب وحدي.
Then be extra cautious.
لذا كن حذرا للغاية.
(Imperial Weaving House)
(دار النسيج الإمبراطورية)
You've deceived me all these years,
لقد خدعتني كل هذه السنوات،
but you did raise me after all.
لكنك قمت بتربيتي بعد كل شيء.
We're even now.
نحن متعادلون الآن.
The imperial seal plan is still in progress.
خطة الختم الإمبراطوري لا تزال قيد التنفيذ.
But all officials are constrained by the Prince Regent.
لكن جميع المسؤولين مقيدين بالأمير الوصي.
The imperial seal alone
الختم الإمبراطوري وحده
can't help you regain power.
لا يمكن أن تساعدك على استعادة الطاقة.
Recently,
حديثاً،
Shi Yu has been courting powerful officials.
لقد كان شي يو يتودد إلى مسؤولين أقوياء.
I fear by the time your poison strikes,
أخشى أنه بحلول الوقت الذي يضرب فيه السم الخاص بك،
you still can't get the seal.
لا تزال غير قادر على الحصول على الختم.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
I always knew you couldn't get the imperial seal,
لقد عرفت دائمًا أنك لا تستطيع الحصول على الختم الإمبراطوري،
so I've secured a better bargaining chip.
لذا فقد حصلت على ورقة مساومة أفضل.
You say Gao Zhiying is with Shi Nan?
هل تقول أن Gao Zhiying مع Shi Nan؟
Yes.
نعم.
He intends to exchange Gao Zhiying
ينوي تبادل Gao Zhiying
for the imperial seal.
للختم الإمبراطوري.
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك،
Gao Zhiying is half-dressed
جاو تشي ينغ يرتدي نصف ملابسه
in prison.
في السجن.
She looks pitiful.
إنها تبدو مثيرة للشفقة.
After all, she saved my life once.
ففي نهاية المطاف، لقد أنقذت حياتي مرة واحدة.
I simply can't...
أنا ببساطة لا أستطيع...
Exchanging her for the seal
استبدالها بالختم
is indeed the fastest solution now.
هو بالفعل الحل الأسرع الآن.
But Gao Ji
لكن جاو جي
is a power-hungry man obsessed with fame.
هو رجل متعطش للسلطة مهووس بالشهرة.
Would he exchange the imperial seal for Gao Zhiying?
هل يستبدل الختم الإمبراطوري بـ جاو تشي ينغ؟
Gao Ji
جاو جي
is ambitious
طموح
and masks his emotions well.
ويخفي مشاعره جيدا.
Yet only Gao Zhiying
ولكن فقط جاو تشي ينغ
can unsettle him.
يمكن أن يزعجه.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
just let them make the exchange.
فقط دعهم يقومون بالتبادل.
It's better the imperial seal is
من الأفضل أن يكون الختم الإمبراطوري
in Shi Nan's hands than in Gao Ji's.
في يد شي نان منه في يد جاو جي.
Given my knowledge about my brother,
بالنظر إلى معرفتي بأخي،
even if he gets the seal,
حتى لو حصل على الختم،
he won't release Gao Zhiying easily.
لن يطلق سراح Gao Zhiying بسهولة.
We must find a way to rescue her.
يجب علينا أن نجد طريقة لإنقاذها.
Where is the waiting maid?
أين الخادمة المنتظرة؟
Change the new garment.
تغيير الملابس الجديدة.
(Inform the Prince Regent.)
(أبلغ الأمير الوصي.)
(Tonight at midnight,)
(في منتصف الليل الليلة)
(in Tiansheng Mountain,)
(في جبل تيانشينغ،)
(exchange the seal for his sister.)
(استبدال الختم بأخته.)
♪Without fate, this dream would fade♪
♪بدون القدر، هذا الحلم سوف يتلاشى♪
♪Without you, my life would quietly end♪
♪بدونك، حياتي ستنتهي بهدوء♪
♪Fade like drifting clouds♪
♪تتلاشى مثل السحب المنجرفة♪
♪Half dream, half illusion♪
♪نصف حلم، ونصف وهم♪
♪Fated or fleeting♪
♪مقدر أو عابر♪
♪Spring breeze falls from my brow♪
♪نسائم الربيع تهب من جبهتي♪
♪Where to go, I do not know♪
♪أين أذهب، لا أعرف♪
♪I turn, and all is gone♪
♪أتحول، وكل شيء قد ذهب♪
♪Ask how deep the dust of love runs♪
♪اسأل عن مدى عمق غبار الحب♪
♪How strong longing grows♪
♪ما أشد الشوق الذي ينمو♪
♪I play till the final note♪
♪ألعب حتى النغمة الأخيرة♪
♪Let fate cut like a blade♪
♪دع القدر يقطع مثل الشفرة♪
♪I bid you one last farewell♪
♪أقول لك وداعا أخيرا♪
♪I know not love's emptiness nor hatred's pain♪
♪لا أعرف فراغ الحب ولا ألم الكراهية♪
♪When we meet again, the snow will melt away♪
♪عندما نلتقي مرة أخرى، سوف يذوب الثلج♪
♪One vow, so deep in love♪
♪عهد واحد، عميق في الحب♪
♪I'd give my life for it♪
♪سأعطي حياتي من أجله♪